荣誉出品
最专业冰火字幕
专注GOT剧集
翻译   Rubilacxe
翻译   波隆史铎克渥斯
翻译   Bran的夏天
君临 King's Landing
翻译   陌客之子
红堡
Red Keep
校对   拉拉兄控凯冯
校对   barrosa
龙石岛
Dragonstone
恐怖堡 Dreadfort
临冬城
Winterfell
后期    加文·维斯特林
监制    临冬城的狮子
策划    baozhenyuawabi
特别顾问   屈畅(ccxx)@史诗图书
绝境长城 the Wall
最专业的华语冰火资料站：                         中文维基
http://zh.asoiaf.wikia.com/
百度冰与火之歌贴吧  &  百度权力的游戏贴吧    联合出品
史诗图书  正统奇幻的圣殿
弥林
Meereen
根据长篇小说
《冰与火之歌》 改编
原著  乔治·R·R·马丁
衣柜字幕组
更多冰火资讯
请扫码关注“黑城堡”微信平台
微信号：HEICHENGBAO
第三集  Breaker of Chains
镣铐破除者
乔佛里·拜拉席恩
铁王座上的王
瑟曦·兰尼斯特
太后
是你干的 是你干的！
You did this.You did this!
- 我们必须走了 - 抓住他！抓住他！
- We have to leave.  - Take him! Take him!
他的老婆在哪儿？
Where is his wife?
珊莎在哪儿？
Where's Sansa?
找到她 封锁城门
Find her.Bar the gates of the city.
泰温·兰尼斯特
凯岩城公爵 国王之手
拦住港口里每一艘船
Seize every ship in the harbor.
- 她在哪儿？！ - 禁止任何人离开首都！
- Where is she?!  - No one leaves the capital!
任何人！
No one!
- 上来 -我们要去哪儿？
- Get in.  - Where are we going?
唐托斯·霍拉德
弄臣
安全的地方
Somewhere safe.
珊莎·史塔克
小恶魔的妻子
上去吧 小姐
Up you go, my lady.
你会没事的
You'll be fine.
你比你想象的更坚强
You're stronger than you know.
- 贝里席大人？ - 培提尔
- Lord Baelish?  - Petyr.
培提尔·贝里席
“小指头”
你没受伤吧 小姐？
Are you hurt, my lady?
很好 很好
Good. Good.
我知道你一定吓坏了 不过放心
I'm sure you've had quite a fright.Rest easy.
- 最难熬的时光已经过去了 - 贝里席大人
- The worst is past.  - Lord Baelish.
- 我保证过会把她安全带到这里 - 安静一点 朋友
- I promised I'd get her to you safely.  - Softly, my friend.
声音在水上传的很远
Voices carry over water.
我必须在有人注意到之前赶回去
I should get back before someone thinks to look for me.
但首先你想拿到报酬
First you'll want your pay.
- 一万金龙 对么？ - 一万金龙
- 10,000 was it?  - 10,000.
等等！
Wait!
嘘
Shh.
你可不想被太后听到吧？
You don't want the queen to hear, do you?
上千金袍子正在四处搜索你的下落
1,000 gold cloaks are searching for you.
要是被他们逮到了
And if they found you,
你觉得他们会怎样惩罚谋杀国王的女孩？
how do you think they would punish the girl who murdered the king?
- 我没有谋杀任何人 - 我知道 我知道
- I didn't murder anyone.  - I know. I know.
但你不得不承认你的嫌疑很大
But you must admit it looks suspicious.
国王处决了你的父亲
The king who executed your father,
还折磨了你这么多年
who tormented you for years,
而你在他被谋杀后逃走了
and you fled the scene of his murder.
你为什么要杀他？
Why did you kill him?
因为他酗酒成性 还愚不可及
Because he was a drunk and a fool
而我信不过愚蠢的酒鬼
and I don't trust drunk fools.
他救了我
He saved me.
救了你？小姐 他只是听我的命令行事
Saved you? My lady,he followed my orders.
他们全都一样 他这么做只是为了金子
Every one of them.And he did it all for gold.
一袋金龙买得一时安全
Money buys a man's silence for a time.
一支好箭可保一世平安
A bolt in the heart buys it forever.
他帮我是因为我救了他的命
He was helping me because I saved his life.
是啊 他还给了你一条珍贵的项链
Yes, and he gave you a priceless necklace
说是他祖母的
that once belonged to his grandmother.
还是霍拉德家族最后的遗物
The last legacy of House Hollard.
实际上是我几周前找人做的
I had it made a few weeks ago.
还记得关于都城我说过什么吗？
What did I once tell you about the capital?
我们都是骗子
We're all liars here.
来吧 小姐
Come, my lady.
我知道这一天对你来说很艰难
I know you've had a difficult day.
但你现在安全了
But you're safe now.
我保证
I promise you that.
你在我身边很安全
You're safe with me
和我一起回家吧
and sailing home.
玛格丽·提利尔
王后
我还是王后么？
So am I the queen?
跟蓝礼那时候比当然是
More than you were with Renly.
奥莲娜·雷德温
“荆棘女王”
玛格丽·提利尔的祖母
但假如乔佛里在死前已经跟你圆房了
Less than you would have been if Joffrey had done you the courtesy
会更名正言顺
of consummating the marriage before dying.
但是现在
In any case, this would not be an opportune moment
不是讨论这个问题的时候
to press the issue.
他抓着自己的喉咙
Clawing at his own throat,
乞求着母亲能救救自己—— 这太恐怖了
looking to his mother to make it stop-- it was horrible.
这世上恐怖的事情太多了
The world is overflowing with horrible things.
但比起死亡都不算什么
But they're all a tray of cakes next to death.
你知道么？你爷爷去世后 他们把我带到他的尸体前
They brought me your grandfather's body when he died, you know?
强迫我看着他
Made me look at it.
当时怎么样？
What was it like?
他们把我带到大厅里 他就在那儿
They took me to the Great Hall and there he was.
我的丈夫
The man I'd married
让我承受生子之痛的人
and suffered to father my children.
让我在冗长的晚宴和乏味的聚会里
A great doughy lump I'd sat next to
枯坐在旁边的那具皮囊
at endless dinners and tedious gatherings.
他就在那儿……
There he was...
躺在台上
lying on a table.
我的一个丈夫喜欢男人的陪伴
One of my husbands preferred the company of men
他被利刃穿心而死
and was stabbed through the heart.
另一个则热衷于折磨小动物
Another was happiest torturing animals
结果在我们的婚宴上被毒杀
and was poisoned at our wedding feast.
- 我一定是被诅咒了 - 胡扯
- I must be cursed.  - Nonsense.
你的处境已经好很多了
Your circumstances have improved markedly.
也许眼睁睁看着他死去并不好受
You may not have enjoyed watching him die,
但我敢说
but you enjoyed it more than you would have enjoyed
要比嫁给他好得多
being married to him,I can promise you that.
但我本该成为王后
But I would have been the queen.
我们和兰尼斯特的联盟
Our alliance with the Lannisters
对我们来说有多么不愉快
remains every bit as necessary to them
对他们来说就有多么重要
as it is unpleasant for us.
乔佛里的事你做的很好
You did wonderful work on Joffrey.
下一个应该会容易许多
The next one should be easier.
托曼·拜拉席恩
乔佛里之弟 王位继承者
你的哥哥死了
Your brother is dead.
你知道这意味着什么吗？
Do you know what that means?
我可不是在哄你
I'm not trying to trick you.
这意味着我将成为国王
It means I'll become king.
是的 你将成为国王
Yes, you will become king.
你觉得你会成为一位怎样的国王？
What kind of king do you think you'll be?
一位好国王？
A good king?
嗯 我也这么想
Mm, I think so as well.
你有成为好国王的气质
You've got the right temperament for it.
但怎样才能做个好国王？嗯？
But what makes a good king? Hmm?
要做一位好国王 最重要的那个品质是什么？
What is a good king's single most important quality?
一定要在这里谈吗
This is hardly the place or the time.
圣洁？
Holiness?
嗯
Hmm.
受祝福的贝勒非常圣洁
Baelor the Blessed was holy.
也非常虔诚
And pious.
他修建了这座教堂
He built this sept.
他还任命一位六岁的男孩为总主教
He also named a six-year-old boy high septon
因为他认为这个男孩能施行神迹
because he thought the boy could work miracles.
最终他早早地把自己送进了坟墓
He ended up fasting himself into an early grave
因为所有食物都来自这个世界
because food was of this world
而这个世界罪孽深重
and this world was sinful.
公正
Justice.
是啊
Yeah.
一位好国王必须公正
A good king must be just.
奥里斯一世就是如此
Orys I was just.
所有人都赞颂他带来的改变
Everyone applauded his reforms.
无论是贵族或是平民
Nobles and commoners alike.
但他的公正并没有持续太久
But he wasn't just for long.
登基不到一年
He was murdered in his sleep
就被他的亲兄弟在睡梦中谋杀了
after less than a year by his own brother.
他能算真正的公正么？
Was that truly just of him?
弃他的臣民于恶魔手中
To abandon his subjects to an evil
仅仅因为自己过于轻信 未能察觉？
that he was too gullible to recognize?
- 不 - 不
- No.  - No.
- 那力量呢？ - 对
- What about strength?  - Yes.
力量
Strength.
劳勃国王拥有力量
King Robert was strong.
他赢得了战争
He won the rebellion
他终结了坦格利安王朝
and crushed the Targaryen dynasty.
但他在位十七年 仅仅出席了
And he attended three small council meetings
三次御前会议
in 17 years.
他把时间都花在嫖妓 狩猎和酗酒上
He spent his time whoring and hunting and drinking
直到后两者害死了他
until the last two killed him.
那么 我们知道了有一个人把自己活活饿死
So, we have a man who starves himself to death,
有一个人被自己的亲兄弟谋杀
a man who lets his own brother murder him,
还有一个人认为赢得战争和统治王国是一回事
and a man who thinks that winning and ruling are the same thing.
他们都缺乏什么？
What do they all lack?
- 智慧 -没错！
- Wisdom.  - Yes!
智慧是成为好国王的关键品质
Wisdom is what makes a good king.
没错
Yes.
但什么是智慧？嗯？
But what is wisdom?Hmm?
一个有着肥沃土地和丰厚财富的家族
A house with great wealth and fertile lands
请求你的保护
asks you for your protection
以对抗另一个有着强大海军
against another house with a strong navy
并且随时可能会反对你的统治的家族
that could one day oppose you.
你怎么知道哪个选择是正确的 哪个不是？
How do you know which choice is wise and which isn't?
你是打理过国库与存粮
You've any experience of treasuries and granaries
还是操练过舰船与士兵？
or shipyards and soldiers?
- 都没有 - 你当然没有
- No.  - No. Of course not.
一位明智的国王明白自己知道什么 不知道什么
A wise king knows what he knows and what he doesn't.
你还年轻
You're young.
一位明智的年轻国王会听取廷臣的建议
A wise young king listens to his counselors
并留心他们的话 直到他长大成人
and heeds their advice until he comes of age.
而最明智的国王
And the wisest kings
则会一直听下去
continue to listen to them long afterwards.
你的哥哥不是个明智的国王
Your brother was not a wise king.
你的哥哥不是个好国王
Your brother was not a good king.
如果他是的话
If he had been,
也许他现在还会活着
perhaps he'd still be alive.
现在 作为国王 你必须成婚
Now, as the king,you will have to marry.
你明白为什么吗？
Do you understand why?
国王需要皇后
A king needs a queen.
对 但为什么？
Yes, but why?
为了延续家族血脉
To further the family line.
- 你知道该怎么做么？ - 是的
- Do you know how that happens?  - Yes.
是的 但有人跟你讲过其中细节么？
Yes, but has anyone explained the details to you?
我想没有
I don't think so.
相对于其他的事情，这其实很简单
It's all relatively straightforward.
- 你还好么？ - 我没事
- How are you?  - I'm all right.
当然 你不会有事的
You are.You will be.
我会确保这一点
I'll see to that.
请给太后和她儿子一些独处的时间
Please give the queen a moment alone with her son.
- 是的 大人 - 你们所有人
- Yes, my lord.  - All of you.
大主教
七神的代言人
詹姆·兰尼斯特
“弑君者”  御林铁卫队长
是提利昂干的
It was Tyrion.
他杀了他
He killed him.
他跟我说过
He told me he would.
“总有一天 当你自以为平安快活时
"A day will come when you think you are safe and happy
喜乐会在嘴里化成灰烬”
and your joy will turn to ashes in your mouth."
这是他对我说的
That's what he said to me.
也是你看到的
You saw it.
你看到小乔指着他 就在他--
You saw Joff point at him just before he--
我不确定我看到了什么
I don't know what I saw.
向他复仇
Avenge him.
为我们的儿子复仇
Avenge our son.
杀了提利昂
Kill Tyrion.
提利昂是我的兄弟
Tyrion's my brother.
我们的兄弟
Our brother.
他会受到审判 我们会知道事情的真相
There'll be a trial. We'll get to the truth of what happened.
我不要什么审判
I don't want a trial.
他会顺着这个机会挪出一条生路来
He'll squirm his way to freedom given the chance.
我要他死
I want him dead.
求求你 詹姆
Please, Jaime.
杀了他
You have to.
他是我们的儿子
He was our son.
我们的宝贝孩子
Our baby boy.
你这可恨的女人
You're a hateful woman.
为什么诸神要让我爱上一个可恨的女人？
Why have the gods made me love a hateful woman?
詹姆 别在这儿 求求你
Jaime, not here, please.
求求你
Please.
停下来
Stop it.
- 停下来 停下 -不
- Stop it. Stop.  - No.
停下来 停下
Stop it.Stop.
停下
Stop.
停下 我们不能这样
Stop. It's not right.
不能这样 不能这样
It's not right.It's not right.
我才不管
I don't care.
- 别  - 我才不管
- Don't.  - I don't care.
- 不要 詹姆 不要  - 我才不管
- Don't. Jaime, don't.  - I don't care.
快要下雨了
Gonna rain soon.
艾丽娅·史塔克
桑铎·克里冈
“猎狗”
我们现在在哪儿？
Where are we?
快到美人市集了 我感觉
Near Fairmarket, I think.
你感觉？
You think?
你没有地图吗？
You don't have a map?
- 我没有  - 我们应该去弄一张
- No, I don't have a map.  - Maybe we should get one.
你要是能找到一家卖地图的我就给你买一张
Just point out the next map shop you see and I'll buy you one.
从这儿到鹰巢城还有多远？
How far is it to the Eyrie?
- 远得很  - 你确定我们没有走错路吗？
- Far.  - And you're sure we're going the right way?
相信我 丫头 我可希望把你尽快送到那儿
Believe me, girl, I want you there as soon as I can.
收了钱 然后再上路
Get my gold, be on my way.
- 上路去哪儿？  - 你管这个干嘛？
- On your way where?  - Why do you care?
或许找艘船到狭海对面去
Might book passage across the Narrow Sea.
当个佣兵
Fight as a sellsword.
也许加入次子团 这名字听起来很适合我
Second Sons, could be.Seems like a good fit for me.
我想去布拉佛斯看看
I'd like to see Braavos one day.
为什么是布拉佛斯？
Why Braavos?
我在那儿有朋友
I have friends there.
我表示怀疑
I doubt it.
七神保佑你
Seven blessings to you.
- 你想干什么？  - 我想干什么？这是我的地盘
- What do you want?  - What do I want? This is my land.
如果我站在这儿 这就是我的地盘
If I'm standing on it,it's my land.
我们只是在饮马 很快就离开
We were just watering the horses.We'll be on our way.
请原谅我父亲
Forgive my father.
他在战斗中负了伤
He was wounded fighting in the war.
他离开的时候 我们的小屋被烧掉了 我母亲也去世了
Our cottage burned down while he was gone and my mother with it.
从那以后他完全变了个人
He's never been the same.
他为哪个家族战斗？
Which house did he fight for?
奔流城的徒利家族
The Tullys of Riverrun.
暴风雨就要来了
There's a storm coming.
你们今晚需要找个地方避雨
You'll be wanting a roof tonight.
谷仓里有新鲜的干草
There's fresh hay in the barn.
And Sally here makes rabbit stew just like her mom used to do.
萨莉会炖兔子 和她母亲以前做的一样
我们可以提供的不多 但我们欢迎每一个
We don't have much,but any man that bled
为徒利家族流血的人
for House Tully is welcome to it.
愿天父仁慈地裁决我们
We ask the Father to judge us with mercy
原谅我们人性的脆弱
accepting our human frailty.
愿圣母保佑我们的作物
We ask the Mother to bless our crops
使我们供养自己和每一个客人
so we may feed ourselves and all who come to our door.
愿战士赐予我们勇气
We ask the Warrior to give us courage
在这个充满了冲突与动荡的时代
in these days of strife and turmoil.
愿少女保护萨莉的纯洁
We ask the Maiden to protect Sally's virtue
让她远离堕落的魔爪
to keep her from the clutches of depravity.
你他妈的非要把七个神都说完吗？
You got to do all seven of the fuckers?
父亲！
Father!
愿铁匠让我们的双手与身躯充满力量
We ask the Smith to strengthen our hands
使我们完成必需的工作
and our backs so we may finish the work required of us.
愿老妪指明我们在黑暗中前进的道路
We ask the Crone to guide us on our journey from darkness to darkness.
愿陌客别他妈的不分青红皂白
And we ask the Stranger not to kill us
在今晚就把我们都杀光
in our beds tonight for no damn reason at all.
我真的很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
汤很棒
Really good.
- 你们参加孪河城的战斗了吗？  - 你管那叫战斗？
- Did you fight at the Twins?  - Call that a fight?
屠宰牲口还差不多
Slaughtering livestock more like.
他们管那叫红色婚礼
The Red Wedding they're calling it.
瓦德·佛雷亵渎了神灵
Walder Frey committed sacrilege that day.
他给了史塔克的人面包和盐 让他们享有宾客权利
He shared bread and salt with the Starks.He offered them guest right.
宾客权利已经没有什么意义了
Guest right don't mean much anymore.
它对我来说还有意义
It means something to me.
七神会为他们复仇
The gods will have their vengeance.
佛雷会因为他的所作所为下七层地狱
Frey will burn in the seventh hell for what he did.
霍斯特·徒利统治河间地的时候可不是这样
Things were different when Hoster Tully ruled the Riverlands.
尽管我们和其他地方的人一样 收成时好时坏
We had good years and bad years, same as anyone.
但我们是安全的 而现在在这帮佛雷治下
But we were safe.Now with the Freys,
强盗们会来抢劫我们的食物 搜刮我们的银子
raiders come plundering, steal our food, steal our silver.
我本想把萨莉送到北境和我的兄弟住在一起
I was gonna send Sally north to stay with my brother,
可北境的情况也不比这儿好 整个王国都变馊了
but the north's no better.The whole country's gone sour.
你有麦酒吗？
You got any ale?
恐怕没有
Afraid not.
怎么会有人家里没有麦酒呢？
How can a man not keep ale in his home?
看起来你好像真的会用那把剑
You look like you could really swing that sword.
是个训练有素的好战士
A real warrior with proper training.
那些强盗肯定不是你的对手
Those raiders wouldn't stand a chance against you.
你在这里呆到下个月怎么样？
How would it be if you stayed on till the new moon?
我可以雇你帮我干农活
I could use a man to help with the farmwork.
萨莉做了她力所能及的
Sally does what she can,
但她可抱不动整整一捆干草
but she can't lift a bale of hay.
如果有毛贼来小偷小摸
And if any thieves came looking for easy pickings,
我敢打赌他们一看到你就得逃跑
one look at you, I'd bet they'd run the other way.
无意冒犯
Meaning no offense.
你能付给我多少？
What'll you pay?
我剩下的钱不多
I don't have much.
但我还在土匪发现不了的地方藏了一点银子
But I have hidden a bit of silver from the bandits.
你干多少活 我就付你多少钱？
Fair wages for fair work?
成交
Fair wages for fair work.
- 你干了什么？  - 去给你的马上鞍
- What did you do?!  - Get your horse saddled.
- 你告诉过我你不是强盗  - 我不是
- You told me you weren't a thief.  - I wasn't.
他带我们进屋 给我们吃的 而你--
He took us in.He fed us and you--
是的 他带我们进了屋 他是个好人
Aye, he took us in.He's a good man
他女儿炖的肉也很好吃
and his daughter makes a nice stew.
但等冬天一到 他们都得死
And they'll both be dead come winter.
- 你怎么能确定 - 我就是确定
- You don't know that. - I do know it.
他很虚弱 他不能保护自己
He's weak. He can't protect himself.
等冬天一到 他们都得死
They'll both be dead come winter.
死人不需要银子
Dead men don't need silver.
你是七国里最坏的混蛋！
You're the worst shit in the Seven Kingdoms.
比我更坏的多了去了
There's plenty worse than me.
我只是懂得生存法则
I just understand the way things are.
还要死多少史塔克你才懂？
How many Starks they got to behead before you figure it out?
强奸犯 强奸犯
Ranger: Raper. Raper.
偷马贼
Horse thief.
第九胎
Ninth born son.
强奸犯
Raper.
小偷 既是小偷又是强奸犯
Thief. Thief and raper.
他在这儿 “杀手”山姆
There he is, Sam the Slayer.
去找你的野人婊子吗？
Going to visit your wildling whore?
- 她不是婊子  - 不是吗？
- She's not a whore. - No?
没准我今晚就给她个铜板 看看她究竟是不是呢
Maybe I'll give her a copper tonight and find out.
他们都认为我在说谎
They all think I'm lying.
说什么谎？
About what?
杀死异鬼的那件事
Killing the white walker.
你没说谎啊
You're not lying.
山姆威尔·塔利
“杀手” 守夜人事务官
吉莉
卡斯特的女儿和妻子
我永远也忘不掉它尖叫的声音
I'll never forget the way it screamed.
但你是唯一一个目击者
But you're the only one that saw it.
而他们却都认为你只是个--
And they all think you're just a--
只是个什么？
A what?
呃 只是个野人
Well, a wildling.
我父亲痛恨这个词
My father hated that word.
我想这也不是什么好词
It's not a very nice word, I suppose.
我不清楚
I don't know.
它让我听起来稍微危险了一点 不是吗？
It makes me sound a bit dangerous, doesn't it?
那...
So...
你过得都还好吗？
are you all right?
没人来骚扰你？
No one bothering you?
有好多人来看我
I get a lot of looks.
我听到他们拿我开玩笑
I hear them making their jokes.
但是没人碰过我 如果你想问这个的话
But no one's touched me if that's what you mean.
我有的时候很担心
I worry about it sometimes.
一直很担心
All the time.
有什么好担心的？
Why do you worry about it?
这儿有一百个男人 却只有你一个女人
100 men, one woman.
我还有其他的事情要考虑
I've got other things to think about.
可这是他们唯一考虑的事情
That's the only thing they think about.
- 你在犯傻  - 我没有犯傻
- You're being silly. - I'm not being silly.
有一百个男人整夜意淫你
There's 100 men lying awake at night picturing you.
那你呢？
What about you?
我？
What about me?
吉莉？
Gilly?
我为你担心
I worry about you.
谢谢你
Thank you.
谢什么？
For what?
谢谢你为我担心
For worrying about me.
我不确定你在这里是否安全
I don't know if you're safe here.
他们是我的兄弟
They're my brothers,
但在来这里之前他们有些是小偷
but some of them were thieves before they came here.
有些是强奸犯
Some of them were rapers.
你看到了他们在你父亲的堡垒做了什么
You saw what they did at your father's keep.
所以你的意思是？
So what are you saying?
或许你在鼹鼠村会更安全
Maybe you'd be safer in Mole's Town.
你厌烦我了吗？
Are you bored of me?
厌烦你？
Bored of you?
我...
I...
我只是想保护你
I want to protect you.
我去把这些带给哈布
I'll get these to Hobb.
照顾一下小山姆
Keep an eye on little Sam.
陛下
Your Grace.
戴佛斯·席渥斯
“洋葱骑士” 史坦尼斯的首相
你现在是个有文化的人了 看看上面说了什么？
You're a literary man now. What do you make of that?
史坦尼斯·拜拉席恩
狭海中的王
- 乔佛里？  -篡夺者乔佛里·拜拉席恩
- Joffrey? - The usurper Joffrey Baratheon.
我曾经念着他的名字把水蛭扔到火里
I said those words when I tossed a leech into the fire.
一只吸满了私生子血液的水蛭
A leech filled with bastard blood.
一个被你放走的私生子
A bastard you set free.
我现在面临着千载难逢的机会
I am now faced with a great opportunity
却没有足够的力量来利用它
and I am powerless to take advantage of it.
我会为您征召一支军队 陛下
I will find you an army, Your Grace.
- 我正在夜以继日地工作--  -而你的进展如何呢？
- I've been working day and night-- - What progress have you made?
我争取到了比兹伯利家族为您作战
I've rallied House Peasebury to your cause.
比兹伯利家族
House Peasebury.
- 穆斯古德家族  - 穆斯古德家族
- House Musgood. - House Musgood.
- 还有海伊家族  -海伊家族
- And House Haigh. - House Haigh.
他们的人加起来都不够去抢个仓库的
They don't have enough men between them to raid a pantry.
世界上并非只有维斯特洛大陆 陛下
Westeros is not the world, Your Grace.
我们需要去东方寻找船只和战士
We need to look east for ships and men.
黄金团有一万名受过训练的士兵
10,000 skilled soldiers fight for the Golden Company.
- 黄金团？  - 他们从未违背过合约
- The Golden Company? - They've never broken a contract.
他们是佣兵
They're sellswords.
我们可以接受用血魔法让您登上王座
We're willing to use blood magic to put you on the throne,
却不能接受雇佣士兵为我们作战吗？
but we're not willing to pay men to fight?
那红袍女的魔法是真的
Now the Red Woman's magic is real.
她的占卜和预言或许也是真的
Her visions and prophecies may be, too,
但我从未听说过靠占卜和预言赢得的战争
but I've never heard of visions and prophecies winning a war.
战争要靠士兵来赢得 实实在在的士兵
Soldiers win wars. Soldiers on the ground.
要靠士兵的流血牺牲
It's dirty on the ground.
可我们没有钱
We don't have any gold.
暂时没有
Not yet.
如果我不能有所作为
If I do not press my claim,
我对王位的宣称就会被遗忘
my claim will be forgotten.
我不会成为别人历史书里的注脚
I will not become a page in someone else's history book.
我的时间不多了 戴佛斯爵士
I'm running out of time, Ser Davos.
这也意味着你的时间不多了
Which means you're running out of time.
你迟到了
You're late.
希琳·拜拉席恩
史坦尼斯·拜拉席恩的女儿
我很抱歉 公主殿下
I'm sorry, Princess.
我以为你不会来了呢
I thought you weren't coming.
国王之手可没有多少闲暇时间
The Hand of the King doesn't have much leisure time.
你要是把骑士读成马奇士可当不好首相
You won't be a very good Hand if you see the word knight and say "ka-nigit."
这事儿有过 几周前吧
That happened once, weeks ago.
毫无疑问 您不愧是您父亲的女儿
You're your father's daughter, no mistake.
你们俩都这么言辞犀利
Bloody relentless, the both of you.
今天读一本新书 复杂的单词挺多的
It's a new one today. Lots of tricky words.
但我觉得您应该应付得来
But I think you can manage.
你光动嘴唇是永远读不好的
You'll never read well if you move your lips.
小孩子才这么读
That's how children do it.
布拉佛斯首席剑士
"The Life and Adventures of Elyo Grivas
艾里奥·格里瓦斯的冒险生涯
First Sword of Braavos."
太感谢您了
Thank you very much.
我喜欢这本书 里面充满了刀剑厮杀还有海盗
I like this one. It's full of sword fights and pirates.
你以前就是个海盗
You were a pirate once.
不 我从没做过海盗 只当过走私者
No, I was never a pirate. I was a smuggler.
有什么区别吗？
What's the difference?
噢 做走私者可不能
Well, if you're a famous smuggler,
远近闻名
you're not doing it right.
我父亲说罪犯就是罪犯
My father says a criminal is a criminal.
您父亲对不良行为的好的方面
Your father lacks an appreciation
缺乏鉴赏力
of the finer points of bad behavior.
布拉佛斯人也一样
So do the Braavosi.
- 你航行到过布拉佛斯？ - 当然
- You've sailed to Braavos? - Of course.
差点被一个布拉佛斯首席剑士砍了头
Almost got beheaded by a First Sword of Braavos.
我试着跟他解释海盗跟走私者之间的区别
I tried to explain to him the difference between pirates and smugglers,
但他也跟您父亲一样 对区分这二者毫无兴趣
but he didn't seem any more interested in the distinction than your father.
要我说 如果您为布拉佛斯的铁金库工作
I suppose if you work for the Iron Bank of Braavos
并且您的每艘运金船都值半个王国
and each one of your gold barges is worth half a kingdom,
您就不会过分关注这两种职业之间的区——
you tend not to be overly concerned with the kind of distinction--
- 你这是干嘛？ - 我需要您写一封信
- What was that for? - I need you to write a message.
你应该自己去写 这是练习的好机会
You should write it yourself. It's good practice.
这消息对我太过重要了
It's too important for me.
我需要一位聪明人来做这事 来吧
I need a smart person to do it. Go on.
传信给布拉佛斯铁金库的办事处
To the offices of the Iron Bank of Braavos
署名维斯特洛唯一正统的国王史坦尼斯·拜拉席恩
from Stannis Baratheon the one true king of Westeros.
但那不是你啊
But that's not you.
我需要引起他们的注意
I need to get their attention.
继续 写吧
Go on. Write.
他也经历了不少奇遇啊 不是吗？
He's seen some adventures, hasn't he?
- 多可爱的小家伙 - 谢谢
- Precious little thing. - Thank you.
- 他叫什么名字？ - 山姆
- What's his name? - Sam.
名字真可爱
Lovely.
那位是孩子的父亲？
That the daddy?
不
No.
孩子的父亲呢？
Where's the daddy?
他死了
He's dead.
哦 你从哪儿来？
Oh. Where you from?
北边
North of here.
北边？
North of here?
你他妈是个野人？
You a fucking wildling?
- 只要管饭和住宿？ - 是的
- Only room and board? - That's right.
她会打扫卫生，会做饭
She'll clean and cook
还可以照顾其他姑娘的孩子
and look after the other girls' babies.
也可以给她找点别的活儿
Could find other work for her, too.
- 不要别的活儿 - 能挣不少钱的
- No other work. - There'd be money.
还能分你点
Give you a piece of it.
绝对不行
No other work.
我保证只要有空我就会回来看你
I promise to come back and visit whenever I can.
你在这儿更安全
You'll be safer here.
要是在黑城堡谁能保护得了你？我吗？
Who's gonna protect you at Castle Black? Me?
在长城以北就是你保护了我
You protected me north of the Wall.
这不一样
This is different.
他们是守夜人的弟兄
They're brothers of the Night's Watch
我不能在他们背后捅刀子
and I can't just stab them in the back
也不能像在卡斯特那里一样一走了之
and I can't run away, which is what we did at Craster's.
你一定要相信我
You have to trust me.
这样对你我都好
It's for the best.
是对你好
Best for you.
噢 吉莉
Oh, Gilly.
请别这样
Please don't.
真贪心
Greedy.
怎么了？
No?
对不起 你很可爱
I'm sorry. You're lovely,
我只是从来没体验过这种
I just never acquired the taste.
你拿我的美人当什么新体验吗？
You're calling my beauty an acquired taste?
没关系 亲爱的 还有更多的等着你呢
That's quite all right, lover. It's more for you.
你亏了啊
Your loss.
奥柏伦·马泰尔
“红毒蛇” 多恩亲王
男孩和女孩
You like them both the same?
- 你都喜欢？ - 你感到很惊讶吗？
- Boys and girls? - Does that surprise you?
人人都应该有所偏爱才对
Everyone has a preference.
那人人都失去了世界上一半的乐趣
Then everyone is missing half the world's pleasure.
那是诸神的杰作 并且让我愉悦至极
The gods made that and it delights me.
这也是诸神的杰作
The gods made this
并且让我愉悦至极
and it delights me.
面对战争 我为多恩而战
When it comes to war, I fight for Dorne.
面对爱情 我来者不拒
When it comes to love, I don't choose sides.
艾拉莉亚·沙德
奥柏伦的情妇
真希望我在你这般年纪时也能如此有活力
I hope I have as much stamina when I'm your age.
你多大了，25？
What are you, 25?
还是孩子
Children.
有朝一日，如果你够幸运的话，
Someday, if you're lucky,
你会惊醒并发现自己老了
you will wake up and realize you are old.
你那翘臀也会跟着下垂
That pretty ass of yours will sag.
小腹变得软塌塌的 后背则在夜里疼个不停
Your belly will grow soft and your back will ache in the night
一头灰发从耳际长出
and gray hairs will sprout from your ears.
再也没有人会想要你
No one will want you anymore.
在那之前一定要做爱做到够啊
Make sure you fucked your fill before that day.
那你呢？
Did you?
他可是多恩的亲王
He is a prince of Dorne.
到死都会有男孩女孩
Girls and boys will line up
排着长队等着跟他做爱
to fuck him till the day he dies.
他们都得排在你后边
They will all have to line up behind you.
- 奥柏伦亲王 - 泰温大人
-  Prince Oberyn. - Lord Tywin.
我们能谈谈吗？
May we have the room?
有事就招呼我 亲爱的
Call my name if you need me, lover.
您要坐下吗？
Would you like to sit?
不了 谢谢
No, thank you.
来点酒？
Some wine?
不必了 谢谢
No, thank you.
- 您外孙的事我很难过 - 是吗？
- I'm sorry about your grandson. - Are you?
我认为不应该让一个孩子为自己的父亲
I don't believe that a child is responsible for the sins of his father.
或者他的外祖父赎罪
Or his grandfather.
死法实在不光彩
An awful way to die.
什么死法？
Which way is that?
您在审问我吗 泰温大人？
Are you interrogating me, Lord Tywin?
有人认为国王是噎死的
Some believe the king choked.
也有些人相信天之所以是蓝色
Some believe the sky is blue because we live
是因为我们居住在一个蓝眼巨人的眼睛里
inside the eye of a blue-eyed giant.
国王是被毒死的
The king was poisoned.
我听说你在学城研究过毒药
I hear you studied poisons at the Citadel.
的确 所以我才知道
I did. This is why I know.
你对我家族的仇恨更是家喻户晓
Your hatred for my family is rather well known.
你这么一位用毒专家来到首都
You arrive at the capital, an expert in poisoning,
几天后我外孙便死于中毒
some days later my grandson dies of poisoning.
相当可疑
Rather suspicious.
那您怎不将我扔进地牢？
Why haven't you thrown me in a dungeon?
你抵达那天就在这家妓院里
You spoke with Tyrion in this very brothel
跟提利昂谈了话
on the day that you arrived.
你们谈了什么？
What did you discuss?
你觉得我们是在一起密谋吗？
You think we conspired together?
我问你们谈了什么？
What did you discuss?
我姐姐的死
The death of my sister.
你将之归咎于我
For which you blame me.
她被魔山强奸并杀害
She was raped and murdered by the Mountain.
魔山只会听命于你
The Mountain follows your orders.
我当然要怪你了
Of course I blame you.
我就站在这儿 没有武器 没有护卫
Here I stand unarmed, unguarded.
我难道不应该担忧吗？
Should I be concerned?
你没有带武器和护卫是因为你了解我的为人
You are unarmed and unguarded because you know me better than that.
我是个理性的人
I am a man of reason.
如果今天我割了你的喉咙
If I cut your throat today,
明天我就会被五马分尸
I will be drawn and quartered tomorrow.
战争中人们会犯下各种罪行
Men at war commit all kinds of crimes
而他们的上级未必知情
without their superiors' knowledge.
这么说你否认自己与伊莉亚之死有关啰？
So you deny involvement in Elia's murder?
毫无关系
Categorically.
我要找魔山谈谈
I would like to speak with the Mountain.
我确信他会喜欢与你聊天的
I'm sure he would enjoy speaking with you.
未必会有他想的那么喜欢
He might not enjoy it as much as he thinks he would.
我可以安排你们二人见面
I could arrange for this meeting.
但你想要点报酬
But you want something in return.
不久将会有一场针对我儿子的审判
There will be a trial for my son.
并且按照惯例，
And as custom dictates,
会由三名法官作出判决
three judges will render a verdict.
我会主持审判
I will preside.
梅斯·提利尔任第二法官
Mace Tyrell will serve as the second judge.
我希望你能出任第三名
I would like you to be the third.
为什么？
Why?
不久之前 提利尔家族还支持蓝礼·拜拉席恩
Not long ago, the Tyrells sided with Renly Baratheon.
而与铁王座为敌
Declared themselves enemies of the throne.
现在他们则是我们最强的盟友
Now they are our strongest allies.
的确 您让提利尔家的姑娘当了王后啊
Well, you made the Tyrell girl a queen.
让我来为你儿子的罪名做判决并不怎么诱人
Asking me to judge at your son's trial isn't quite as tempting.
我还会邀请你参加御前会议
I will also invite you to sit on the small council
出任新任国王的首席顾问之一
to serve as one of the new king's principal advisors.
我从未料到你会对多恩有如此尊重 泰温大人
I never realized you had such respect for Dorne, Lord Tywin.
如果没有多恩的效忠我们就称不上七大王国了
We are not the Seven Kingdoms until Dorne returns to the fold.
国王已死 葛雷乔伊家族公然叛乱
The king is dead. The Greyjoys are in open rebellion.
一支野人大军则在向长城进军
A wildling army marches on the Wall.
而在东方 一个坦格利安女孩弄出了三条龙
And in the East, a Targaryen girl has three dragons.
不久之后她的目光就会盯上维斯特洛
Before long, she will turn her eyes to Westeros.
只有多恩成功抵挡过
Only the Dornish managed to resist
伊耿·坦格利安和他的龙
Aegon Targaryen and his dragons.
你是说你需要我们吗？
You're saying you need us?
你对此肯定难以承认
That must be hard for you to admit.
我们需要彼此
We need each other.
你帮我为国王的杀手主持公道
You help me serve justice to the king's assassins
我就帮你为伊莉亚主持公道
and I will help you serve justice to Elia's.
波德瑞克
Podrick.
提利昂·兰尼斯特
“小恶魔” 财政大臣
波德瑞克·派恩
提利昂的侍从
抱歉，这儿太臭了
Apologies for the stench.
我给您带了点酒，大人，但是被他们给拿走了
I brought you some wine, my lord, but they took it from me.
高尚之举
A noble effort.
但他们没找到蜡烛
They didn't find the candles, though.
一个羽毛笔 几卷羊皮纸
A quill, some parchment,
鸭肉香肠 杏仁
duck sausage, almonds,
还有点硬奶酪
and some hard cheese.
你真是个好小伙子
You're a good lad.
有雪伊的消息吗？
Any word of Shae?
什么都没听说 大人
I've heard nothing, my lord.
那这就是好消息
I suppose that's a good thing.
他们在外面是怎么说我的
What are they saying about me out there?
两星期后你会以谋杀国王的罪名
You're to stand trial in a fortnight
接受审判
for murdering the king.
你相信是我杀了乔佛里吗？
Do you believe I murdered Joffrey?
不，大人
No, my lord.
不是您吧？
You didn't?
不 天哪 当然不是
No. Gods, no.
虽然这世界没了他会更好
The world is a better place without him,
但我什么都没做
but I had nothing to do with it.
我觉得
I would like to think
如果是我策划这起皇室谋杀
if I were arranging a royal assassination,
我才不会安排自己站在那儿
I'd plan it in such a way that I wouldn't be standing there
像个傻子一样看着国王死掉
gawking like a fool when the king died.
审判将在两星期后举行
Trial in a fortnight.
他们公布法官是谁了吗？
Have they announced the judges yet?
-有您父亲 -当然了
- Your father. - Of course.
梅斯·提利尔
Mace Tyrell.
那家伙只会按我父亲的意思来
Who will vote exactly as my father tells him to vote.
以及多恩的奥伯伦亲王
And Prince Oberyn of Dorne.
奥伯伦?
Oberyn?
真服了我父亲
Give it to my father.
就算是家族悲剧他也没忘了从中渔利
He never fails to take advantage of a family tragedy.
您得给我个名单 大人
I'm supposed to get a list of names from you, my lord.
列出肯为您作证的人
Anyone who might testify on your behalf.
噢 我可以联系自己的证人吗？
Oh, I can call my own witnesses?
瞧他们多慷慨
How generous of them.
那好吧 我老婆 珊莎
Very well, my wife. Sansa.
大人 她不见了
My lord, she's gone.
-不见了？ -婚礼之后就没人再见过她了
- Gone? - No one's seen her since the wedding.
您觉得会不会是她...
You don't think she...
没有人比珊莎有更多的动机要杀乔佛里了
No one had more cause to kill Joffrey than Sansa,
但刺客并不是她
but the girl is no assassin.
不管是谁杀了国王 他都想让我用脑袋为他买单
Whoever killed the king wanted me to lose my head for it.
而老婆一失踪 我看上去就更加有罪了
And with my wife's disappearance, it makes me seem that much more guilty.
-波德瑞克 -在 大人？
- Podrick. - Yes, my lord?
-他们现在该找上你了 -谁？
- They'll be following you now. - Who will?
我不知道是谁 就是他们 他们那些坏家伙
I don't know. They. They. The ominous they.
那些想置我于死地的男人 女人们 我父亲
The man pulling the strings. Or woman. My father.
也许乔佛里对他们来说太麻烦了
Maybe Joffrey was too much work for him.
乖巧的托曼更方便操纵
Sweet Tommen will be so much easier to handle.
每当不幸的事情降临在我头上
Whenever something bad happens to me,
我猜都有我姐姐的份
I assume it's my sister that had a hand in it.
但不管怎么说
But say what you will of Cersei,
瑟曦爱她的孩子们
she loves her children.
她是唯一一个我确定与这起谋杀毫无瓜葛的人
She is the only one I'm certain had nothing to do with this murder.
真是稀罕
Which makes it unique
明明君临所有的谋杀案她都有份
as King's Landing murders go.
还有其他证人吗 大人？
Any other witnesses, my lord?
瓦里斯要有那个胆 也许能为我作证
Varys could vouch for me if he dared.
他已经受召成为王后方的证人了
He's already been called as a witness for the queen.
果然如此 去找波隆 我有活要交给他
Of course. Fetch Bronn. I have a job for him.
我已经去过了 大人
I've already asked, my lord.
-他们不让他见您 -为什么？
- They won't let him see you. - Why not?
-他们说他是个臭名昭著的杀手 是您的狗腿子
They say he's a known cutthroat and your close associate.
他自身难保
He's under investigation himself.
我哥哥呢？他们至少会允许我见詹姆吧？
And my brother? Will they at least allow me to see Jaime?
我去问问 大人
I'll ask, my lord.
还有些事 大人
There's something else, my lord.
有个人 我没看清他的长相
A man, I didn't know his face,
他来问我能否指证您
he came to ask if I'd testify against you.
说只要我告诉法官
Said I'd be named Ser Podrick Payne
你之前购买过一种叫扼死者的毒药 就封我为波德瑞克·派恩爵士
if I told the judges you'd bought a poison called the Strangler.
波德瑞克·派恩爵士？
Ser Podrick Payne?
听起来不错 你怎么回答的？
Has a nice ring to it. What did you tell him?
我什么都没说 大人
I didn't tell them anything, my lord.
你要接受他们的条件吗？
Are you going to accept their offer?
大人
My lord.
要你指证我可不仅仅是什么建议
Testifying against me wasn't a suggestion.
如果他们用胡萝卜吸引不了你
If they can't tempt you with honey,
就该换大棒了
they'll choose something less sweet.
你一向待我不薄 大人
You've been good to me, my lord.
波德 审判在两周之后举行
Pod, the trial's in a fortnight.
他们要在那之前得到答复
They'll want an answer before that.
我已经给了他们答复 大人
I already gave them an answer, my lord.
我不要你为我而死
I will not have you dying on my behalf.
听见没有？如果我不得不
Do you hear me? If I have to take
经过重重审判 然后去刑场挨上一刀
that long walk to the executioner's block,
我不想看到你的脑袋已经早早挂在上面了
I don't want to see your head already mounted.
-大人 -波德 我命令你
- My lord. - Pod, I am giving you an order.
去找我哥哥 告诉他我需要他
Go and find my brother. Tell him I need him.
然后赶紧离开君临
And get yourself out of King's Landing
趁现在还不晚
before it's too late.
波德！
Pod!
这次是永别了
This is farewell.
别了 大人
Farewell, my lord.
波德
Pod.
再没有比你更忠心的侍从了
There has never lived a more loyal squire.
妈妈说该吃饭了
Mother says it's time to eat.
她煮了什么？等等 等等 让我猜一猜
What's she got boiling? Wait. Wait. Let me guess.
-土豆 -土豆
- Potatoes. - Potatoes.
嗯 没人比你妈妈更会煮土豆了
Well, no one boils a potato better than your mom.
她有没有——
Has she got--
野人来了！
The wildlings!
耶哥蕊特
“火吻而生” 野人
戈蒙！
Guymon!
躲起来
Hide.
快躲起来！
Hide!
托蒙德
“巨人克星” 野人
斯迪
瑟恩的马格拿 野人
你知道怎么去黑城堡吗？
You know how to get to Castle Black?
知道 知道
Yes. Yes.
那是你父母吗？
Those your parents?
睁大眼睛看看
Open your eyes.
我要吃了他们
I'm going to eat them.
听到了吗
Do you hear me?
我要吃了你死去的妈妈
I'm going to eat your dead mama
再吃了你死去的爸爸
and I'm going to eat your dead papa.
去给黑城堡里的乌鸦们报信儿吧
Go tell the crows at Castle Black.
我们得让这些食人生番尝尝教训
We need to teach them a lesson about the way we deal with their kind.
是啊！是啊！
Aye! Aye!
割了他们的喉咙 把他们的尸体
Three dozen bodies with slit throats
从长城上扔下去
tossed off the top of the Wall.
琼恩·雪诺
守夜人事务官
-这样应该能让他们长点记性 -是啊！
- Seems like that would be a good lesson. - Aye!
如果我们出去追击 就正中他们下怀了
If we go after them, we'll be giving them what they want.
杰诺斯·史林特
守夜人
前都城守备队队长
他们想把我们引出去
They want to draw us out,
然后各个击破
pick us off a few at a time.
我们只有一百多人
We have just over 100 men.
这还包括了事务官和工匠
And that's including stewards and builders.
伊蒙·坦格利安
守夜人学士
以及我这样的 我们一个人都损失不起
And me. We can't afford to lose a single man.
我们必须牢记自己的首要职责
We must remember our first responsibility.
艾里沙·索恩
守夜人教头
我们是长城上的守卫
We are the watchers on the Wall.
总得想点办法保护他们的才对
There's got to be a way to protect them.
派普尔
“派普” 守夜人
你是平民的守护者 雪诺大人
You're a champion of the common people, Lord Snow.
你对派普兄弟的建议有什么要说的吗？
What do you say to Brother Pyp's proposition?
奥赛尔·亚威克
守夜人首席工匠
曼斯·雷德近在眼前
Mance Rayder is coming.
如果野人越过了长城
If the wildlings breach the Wall,
他们将席卷千里内的一切
they'll roll over everything and everyone for 1,000 miles
直到遭遇能抵挡他们的军队为止
before they reach an army that can stop them.
我们必须坚守黑城堡
We need to shore up Castle Black
我们必须守卫长城
and we need to defend the Wall.
这才是我们的职责
That is our job.
游骑兵回来了
Rangers returning.
帮帮他
Help him.
还以为你变成蓝眼尸鬼了呢
Thought you'd have blue eyes by now.
你们怎么去了那么久
What took you so long?
-我们被困住了 -被什么？
- We were held up. - By what?
镣铐
Chains.
我们被卡斯特堡垒里的叛乱者扣留了
We were guests of the mutineers at Craster's Keep.
葛兰
“笨牛” 守夜人游骑兵
艾迪森·托勒特
“忧郁的艾迪” 守夜人事务官
-叛乱者还在那里？ -他们哪也没去
- And the mutineers stayed? - They're not going anywhere.
他们抢了卡斯特的食物和老婆
They've got Craster's food and his wives.
可怜的姑娘们
Poor girls.
真没想到 她们也会有想念父亲的时候
Never thought they'd miss their daddy.
卡尔现在成了他们的头
Karl's running things now.
就是他一刀捅进了卡斯特的嘴里
He's the one who put a knife through Craster's mouth.
我们得向北去 杀了他们
We need to ride north and kill them all.
这事先放一放 小子
We just went over this, boy.
-正义可以等 -这与正义无关
- Justice can wait. - It's not about justice.
我告诉野人我们仅仅在黑城堡就有一千人
I told the wildlings we had over 1,000 men at Castle Black alone.
但卡尔那伙人跟我们一样知道真相
Karl and the others know the truth as well as we do.
一旦野人开始严刑逼供
How long do you think they'll keep that information to themselves
你觉得他们还能保密多久？
when the wildlings are peeling their fingernails off?
曼斯要击溃我们轻而易举 只是他还不知道而已
Mance has all he needs to crush us, he just doesn't know it yet.
一旦他抓到了他们就完了
As soon as he gets his hands on them, he will.
然后他就会对我们发动全面进攻
Then he'll throw his full strength at us.
即使我们每个人都能杀掉一百个野人
And even if every one of us kills 100 wildlings,
也依然完全无法抵挡他们前进的脚步
there's still not a thing we can do to stop them.
我可不觉得我能杀一百个野人
I don't think I can kill 100 wildlings.
丹妮莉丝·坦格利安
“风暴降生” 龙之母
他们要进攻吗？
Are they attacking?
只有一名骑手
A single rider.
弥林的勇士
A champion of Meereen.
他们要您派出自己的勇士与他决斗
They want you to send your own champion against him.
巴利斯坦·赛尔弥
女王铁卫 “无畏的”
乔拉·莫尔蒙
“大熊” 女王铁卫
弥桑黛
丹妮莉丝·坦格利安的侍女
他在干什么？
What is he doing?
我觉得他是要...
I believe he means to...
他说我们的军队虽然由男人组成 却没有 男根
He says that we're an army of men without man parts.
还说您根本不是女人 而是个...
He claims you are no woman at all, but a man who...
把老二藏在自己屁眼里的男人
hides his cock in his own asshole.
不要管他 陛下 都是些废话
Ignore him, Your Grace. These are meaningless words.
如果半个城的人都在听 就不是废话了
They're not meaningless if half the city you intend to take is listening to them.
我有话要对弥林的人民说
I have something to say to the people of Meereen.
但首先 我要这家伙安静下来
First, I will need this one to be quiet.
可有勇士愿意迎战？
Do I have a champion?
请将这一荣幸赐予我 龙之母
灰虫子
无垢者指挥官
我不会辜负您
你是无垢者的指挥官
我不能拿你冒险
陛下 我赢过的单挑比世上的任何人都多
Your Grace, I've won more single combats than any man alive.
所以你必须留在我身边
Which is why you must remain by my side.
我比他们中任何一人服侍您的时间都长 卡丽熙
I've been by your side longer than any of them, Khaleesi.
今天也让我为您而战吧
Let me stand for you today as well.
你是我最信赖的谋臣
You are my most trusted advisor,
我最重要的将军 我最宝贵的朋友
my most valued general, and my dearest friend.
我不会拿你的性命作赌注
I will not gamble with your life.
我是最后一个加入您军队的
I was the last to join your army.
我不是什么将军或者女王铁卫
I'm not your general or a member of your Queensguard
达里奥·纳哈里斯
次子团团长
也不是无垢者的指挥官
or the commander of your Unsullied.
我母亲是个妓女 我生来一文不名
My mother was a whore. I come from nothing.
要不了多久 也会身归尘土
And before long, I will return to nothing.
让我为你宰了这家伙吧
Let me kill this man for you.
很好
Very well.
你的观众可不少
You have quite an audience.
要对得起他们
Make it worth their while.
他很英勇 陛下
He is very brave, Your Grace.
是啊 无论输赢
Yes, win or lose,
整个城市都看着呢
as long as the whole city is watching.
你真的不要匹马？
You sure you don't want a horse?
为什么我需要马？
Why would I want a horse?
马比人快得多
Horses are faster than men.
马比人笨得多
Horses are dumber than men.
我乃风暴降生 丹尼莉丝
你们的伟主大人也许对我出言诽谤
又或者对我只字不提
西茨达拉·佐·洛拉克
弥林贵族
没有关系
我没有什么好对他们说的
我只说给你们听
起初 我去了阿斯塔波
那些曾在阿斯塔波身为奴隶的人
现在就站在我身后
身为自由之人
接着 我去了渊凯
那些曾在渊凯身为奴隶的人
现在就站在我身后
身为自由之人
现在我来到了弥林
我不是你们的敌人
你们的敌人就在身旁
你们的敌人偷窃并杀死你们的孩子
你们的敌人什么都没有给你们 除了镣铐和折磨
以及命令
我给你们的不是命令
我给你们的是选择
还有给你们的敌人应得的惩罚
前进！
开火！
衣柜字幕组出品